Now let's look at the next capability of Amazon SageMaker and this is in the deploy and monitor
phase. So it's called as SageMaker model monitor. Now again we're going to discuss this in
lot more detail in the responsible AI section. So I'm just going to give you a 30 second overview
of what SageMaker model monitor does. It is used in the production environment and it monitors
the data quality that is being used for inferencing. So if there is a deterioration in the
data quality that is being used in the production environment for inferencing compared to
what was used during the training phase. So let's say if there are any missing columns, null values
compared to the training phase, then it's going to monitor and alert. Next it also monitors
the model performance based on certain metrics that you might have set. And when the performance
goes below that threshold, it is going to alert and you may require to retrain the model.
So we're going to discuss this in a lot more detail as I said in the responsible AI section.
Next we have the machine learning governance tools such as role manager, model cards and model
dashboard. So again we're going to discuss this as part of the responsible AI section,
but let me just give you a high level 30 second overview. So Amazon SageMaker provides governance
tools to implement machine learning responsibly. So as part of the governance tools, you have the
Amazon SageMaker role manager, which allows admin to create, I am roles for some pre-configured
role personas such as data scientist, data engineer and ML ops engineer. Then we also have
SageMaker model cards, which allow you to capture retrieve and share model information. So you
can capture all the details related to the model like problem type, algorithm used,
name of the model and so on through model cards. And then finally, the third thing within
machine learning governance is model dashboard. So all the details that you capture through the
model cards are visible through this model dashboard. And then finally, we have the SageMaker
jumpstart and we discussed the Amazon SageMaker jumpstart previously where we said it's a fully
managed service that allows access to different models in the area, foundation models, computer
vision models, NLP. Okay, so these are the seven most important capabilities from SageMaker
that you must know. And these have been explicitly called out in the exam guide. So I have put more
emphasis on them. Now, there are a few more capabilities that you should know at a high level
and I will discuss those. Now, let's go and discuss about SageMaker model registry. And this
is in the deploy and monitor phase. So previously, when we were looking at machine learning
development life cycle, we said that model registry can be used to fetch artifacts to run the
model. And this is where SageMaker model registry comes into play. So now let's go and take a look
at some of the key features for SageMaker model registry. So the first one is model versioning.
So it can be used to track and manage different versions of the model. So you can see here in
the screenshot. So we have the model registry and we have the version three of the model. So you
can track all the versions of the model. Next, it is used for metadata management. So you can store
extensive metadata for each model, including training data, hyperparameters, and evaluation
metrics in the SageMaker model registry. So you can see here in the screenshot. So we have the model
registry and name of the model is mlops demo. And then you have the model version. And then you
have some metadata related to this model. So you have the model group, ECR, location, and so on.
Next, it also manages the approval status of the model. So you can see here the status for this
particular model mlops demo is pending. So once you register the model with the model registry,
it needs to be approved before it can be deployed in the production environment.
And then finally post the approval, you can deploy the model to production. So that's at a high
level SageMaker model registry and its key features.